Rockwell Kent
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Alphabetical Files, circa 1900-1971, undated, Series 1:; (Reels 5153-5249, 5256, 5740-5741)
  - The Arts Bureau of Gartner and Bender, Inc., 1946 (Reel 5158, Frame 1241-1245)
  - Arts Council of Japanese Americans for Democracy, undated (Reel 5158, Frame 1246-1248)
  - Asgaard Dairy Case, 1948-1949, undated (Reel 5158, Frame 1249-1392)
    (concerns boycott of Kent's dairy due to his support of Henry Wallace for president; includes letters canceling orders, clippings, legal papers transferring ownership to remaining employees, and letters of support)
  - Ashley, Julia, 1941 (Reel 5158, Frame 1393-1395)
  - Ashworth, John, 1945 (Reel 5158, Frame 1396-1398)
  - Assade, Liuba (see also: Solov, Liuba), 1962-1971 (Reel 5158, Frame 1399-1519)
  - Associated American Artists, Inc., 1941-1947, 1953, 1969-1970 (Reel 5158, Frame 1520-1574)
    (concerns exhibitions, sales, and commissions)
  - Associated American Artists, Inc., cont. (Reel 5159, Frame 3-92)
  - Associated Gallery of Art (see: Bruck, Lorraine) (Reel 5159)
  - Associated Magazine Contributors, Inc., 1946 (Reel 5159, Frame 93-109)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, Inc., 1956 (Reel 5159, Frame 110-114)
  - Astor, Mme., 1936 (Reel 5159, Frame 115-117)
  - Atkins, Arthur, 1956 (Reel 5159, Frame 118-120)
  - Attorneys, 1940-1970 (Reel 5159, Frame 121-1281)
    (correspondence with Leonard Boudin and other lawyers concerning personal, professional, and dairy business, including: divorce from Frances, settling disputes with publishers and other clients, warnings about libelous passages in his writings, daughter Kathleen's problems collecting alimony and child support payments, taxes, estate of mother, real estate transactions, Kent's will and estate planning, visa and passport applications)
  - Auerbach, Pollak & Richardson, 1950-1953 (Reel 5159, Frame unfilmed)
    (correspondence and statements regarding investments)
  - August, Charles, 1914-1915 (Reel 5159, Frame 1283-1291)
  - AuSable Branch of the Delaware and Hudson Railroad Corp. Lawsuit (see also: Train), 1930 (Reel 5159, Frame 1292-1415)
    (correspondence, legal documents, and printed matter about preventing discontinuation of passenger service)
  - AuSable Valley Telephone Company, Inc., 1947-1952 (Reel 5159, Frame 1416-1422)
  - Authors League of America, 1944 (Reel 5159, Frame 1423-1425)
  - Autobiography (It's Me, O Lord; see also: It's Me, O Lord; and This Is My Own), 1953-1958 (Reel 5159, Frame 1426-1561)
    (correspondence with publishers, research letters, arrangements for illustrations, 1953-1953; also, fan mail, 1955-1958)
  - Autobiography (It's Me, O Lord), cont. (Reel 5160, Frame 3-193)
  - Avery, Anne (see also: Kent, Sarah Holgate), 1941-1961, 1966 (Reel 5160, Frame 194-237)
    (correspondence with companion of Sarah Holgate Kent [mother])
  - Avery, George E., 1937-1941 (Reel 5160, Frame 238-253)
  - Avery, Terry, 1969 (Reel 5160, Frame 254-258)
  - Axelrod, Betty, 1957 (Reel 5160, Frame 259-261)
  - Axelsen, A. B., 1956-1957 (Reel 5160, Frame 262-268)
  - N. W. Ayer & Son, 1926-1930, 1945-1946, 1951-1952 (Reel 5160, Frame 269-441)
    (orders for commercial work with comments on sketches; invitations)
  - Aymar, Gordon C., 1928-1949 (Reel 5160, Frame 442-523)
    (request to write introduction to his book about advertising illustration; also concerns Kent illustration for other books edited by Aymar)
  - A, Unidentified (Reel 5160, Frame 524-531)
    (C. W. A., undated; J. H. G. A., 1959)
  - Bacon, Betty, 1953-1961 (Reel 5160, Frame 532-540)
  - Bacon, Prall Grant (Mrs. Marshal L. Bacon), 1954 (Reel 5160, Frame 541-546)
  - Bailey, Frank, 1944 (Reel 5160, Frame 547-550)
  - Baily, Harold James, 1944 (Reel 5160, Frame 551-555)
  - Bajalia, Mrs. Albert, 1945 (Reel 5160, Frame 556-558)
  - G. A. Baker & Co., Inc., 1926 (Reel 5160, Frame 559-561)
  - Baker, Keith, 1941 (Reel 5160, Frame 562-564)
  - Balch Autograph Collection (Albert S. Balch), undated (Reel 5160, Frame 565-567)
  - Baldwin, C. B., 1951 (Reel 5160, Frame 568-570)
  - Baldwin, Henry T., 1946-1953 (Reel 5160, Frame 571-581)
  - Baldwin, Leon C., 1948 (Reel 5160, Frame 582-585)
  - Balk, Christina and Robert, undated, 1949-1956 (Reel 5160, Frame 586-601)
  - Balken, Nick (Edward), 1955-1960 (Reel 5160, Frame 602-702)
    (correspondence about travel to the USSR and exhibition there; Kent family news)
  - Balkovic, Zlatko, 1945 (Reel 5160, Frame 729-734)
  - P. Ballantine & Sons, 1943-1951 (Reel 5160, Frame 703-725)
  - The Ballaton Journal, 1954 (Reel 5160, Frame 726-728)
  - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1941 (Reel 5160, Frame 735-737)
  - Bamer, Delbert, 1946 (Reel 5160, Frame 738-741)
  - Bancroft, Bert, 1951-1956 (Reel 5160, Frame 742-753)
  - Banff, Canada, 1952-1968, undated (Reel 5160, Frame 754-1055)
    (plans and arrangements for 1952 trip; correspondence with friends about family news; comments on Kent's work; information about McCarthy investigations; printed matter on the region and Banff School of Fine Arts; see also: Reed, Gordon and Kate)
  - Bangor Public Library, 1949 (Reel 5160, Frame 1056-1062)
  - Bang's Disease Test (Cattle), 1940-1945 (Reel 5160, Frame unfilmed)
  - Banker, Carl, 1943 (Reel 5160, Frame 1065-1068)
  - Banker, Grace, 1940-1941 (Reel 5160, Frame 1069-1073)
  - Banks, 1925, 1944-1965 (Reel 5160, Frame unfilmed)
    (farm account and personal banking records)
  - Bannister, Estrid (see also: Good, Estrid), 1934-1963, undated (Reel 5160, Frame 1074-1187)
    (correspondence about translation of Salamina into Danish; death of Salamina [Fleicher Moller]; Salamina Fund; family news; Kent on McCathyism)
  - Bannister, Geoffrey, 1954-1955 (Reel 5160, Frame 1188-1192)
  - Barbizon Plaza Hotel, 1943 (Reel 5160, Frame 1193-1195)
  - Barlow, Samuel M. and Ernesta, 1941 (Reel 5160, Frame 1196-1202)
  - Barlowe, Jerry C., 1961 (Reel 5160, Frame 1203-1206)
  - Barnard & Simons Co., Inc., 1945 (Reel 5160, Frame 1207-1210)
  - A. S. Barnes & Company, 1949 (Reel 5160, Frame 1211-1215)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1963 (Reel 5160, Frame 1216-1219)
  - Barnes, Julius H., 1945 (Reel 5160, Frame 1220-1222)
  - Barnett, Lincoln, 1968 (Reel 5160, Frame 1223-1227)
  - Mary Gaston Barnwell Foundation, 1936-1937 (Reel 5160, Frame 1228-1259)
    (correspondence concerning arrangements for Kent's Barnwell Address at Central High School, Philadelphia, with a transcript of his talk, "Art Is for Everyone")
  - Baroody, Jamil, 1944-1947 (Reel 5160, Frame 1260-1297)
  - Barr, Norman and Louise, 1943-1947 (Reel 5160, Frame 1298-1458)
    (correspondence about: Artists League of America, World War II, Kent family news; news of Norman Barr in the service, through his mother, Louise)
  - Barrett Art Gallery, 1947 (Reel 5160, Frame 1459-1462)
  - Barrette, Clifton A., 1969 (Reel 5160, Frame 1463-1467)
  - Barringer, Laura Graham, 1948 (Reel 5160, Frame 1468-1474)
  - Barrows, Alice, undated, 1941-1950 (Reel 5160, Frame 1475-1507)
  - Barth, Lawrence, 1946-1947 (Reel 5160, Frame 1508-1559)
    (correspondence about Barth's writings on American culture and the use of psychology in political work, with copies of his articles)
  - Barth, Lawrence, cont. (Reel 5161, Frame 3-22)
  - Bartlett, Bob, 1915 (Reel 5161, Frame 23-32)
  - Bartlett, Mary J., undated (Reel 5161, Frame 33-36)
  - Barton, Eleanor, undated (Reel 5161, Frame 37-40)
  - Barton, Lyman G. and Ethel, 1954-1957, 1963-1968 (Reel 5161, Frame 41-59)
  - Barton, Philip B., 1951, 1961 (Reel 5161, Frame 60-65)
  - Bartz, Fred, 1956-1971 (Reel 5161, Frame 66-113)
  - Bassett, Norman and Sally (see also: Demco Library Supplies), 1962-1968 (Reel 5161, Frame 114-162)
  - Ted Bates Incorporated, 1943 (Reel 5161, Frame 163-165)
  - Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborne, 1946 (Reel 5161, Frame 166-169)
    (about advertising work)
  - Bauerberg, Dr. Paul J., undated (Reel 5161, Frame 170-172)
  - Baugild, Mary and Albert, 1946-1970 (Reel 5161, Frame 173-250)
    (correspondence about mutual friends and Kent collectors in the Chicago area; Kent's autobiography)
  - Baum, Marjorie Jane, 1947 (Reel 5161, Frame 251-255)
  - Bauman, Mr. and Mrs. Mordecai, 1950-1951 (Reel 5161, Frame 256-259)
  - Baxter, Mr., 1922 (Reel 5161, Frame 260-262)
  - Bayer, Minna, 1965-1966 (Reel 5161, Frame 263-270)
  - A. G. Beaman Agency, Limited, 1936 (Reel 5161, Frame 271-273)
  - Bean, Lawrence W., 1941, 1947 (Reel 5161, Frame 274-279)
  - Bech, George, 1940 (Reel 5161, Frame 280-283)
  - Beck, John H., 1960 (Reel 5161, Frame 284-287)
  - Beck, Mrs. L. V., 1959 (Reel 5161, Frame 288-292)
  - Beck, Torben, 1938-1939 (Reel 5161, Frame 293-320)
  - Becker, Jim and Frances, 1952-1970, undated (Reel 5161, Frame 321-492)
  - Becker, Maurice, 1955-1960 (Reel 5161, Frame 493-509)
    (correspondence concerning the house Kent built for his mother on Monhegan Island, Maine; request for information about getting Becker's paintings included in the Art of Today Collection (Friendship House, Moscow))
  - Bedacht, Max, 1947-1968, undated (Reel 5161, Frame 510-551)
    (correspondence about the 1948 presidential election and the need for a functioning Socialist Party in the U.S.; Kent's trip to the USSR)
  - Beechepies, Marie, 1949 (Reel 5161, Frame 552-555)
  - Beecher, John, 1941 (Reel 5161, Frame 556-558)
  - Belfrage, Mary and Cedric, 1962-1965 (Reel 5161, Frame 559-568)
  - Belknap, Cyril, 1946 (Reel 5161, Frame 569-572)
  - Bell, John A., 1946 (Reel 5161, Frame 573-575)
  - Bell, William and Helen, 1942-1943 (Reel 5161, Frame 576-586)
  - Bemelman, Ludwig, 1941-1942 (Reel 5161, Frame 587-591)
  - Bendix, Hans, 1941 (Reel 5161, Frame 592-597)
  - Benezech, Monique and Jean, n.d, 1952-1970 (Reel 5161, Frame 598-664)
    (correspondence including: Kent's views on the 1952 presidential election and the state of civil liberties in the U.S.; also, family news and Kent's struggle to obtain a passport)
  - Benham, Mr. and Mrs. Stanley, 1941 (Reel 5161, Frame 665-667)
  - Bennett College, 1966 (Reel 5161, Frame 668-670)
  - Bennett, Melba, 1939 (Reel 5161, Frame 671-676)
  - Bennington Drama Festival, 1946 (Reel 5161, Frame 677-680)
  - Benton & Bowles, Inc. (see also: Gerard, Sanford (Jerry), 1945-1947 (Reel 5161, Frame 681-825)
    (concerning advertising illustrations for bituminous coal clients)
  - Benton, Charles, 1957-1966 (Reel 5161, Frame 826-849)
  - Benton, William, 1957-1965 (Reel 5161, Frame 850-873)
  - Berkshire School, 1965 (Reel 5161, Frame 874-877)
  - Bernal, Professor, 1959, 1963 (Reel 5161, Frame 878-881)
  - Berney, Matilda and Leon (Bernie), 1948-1970 (Reel 5161, Frame 882-974)
    (correspondence about Kent's autobiography, passport case, 1956 presidential election, exhibition in the USSR, and Moscow travel plans)
  - Bernhard, Lucian, 1966-1969 (Reel 5161, Frame 975-990)
  - Bernstein, Burt and Ellen, 1969-1970 (Reel 5161, Frame 991-1004)
  - Bernstein, Irene, 1960 (Reel 5161, Frame 1005-1010)
  - Bernstein, Violet (Mrs. Irving D. Bernstein), 1949 (Reel 5161, Frame 1011-1013)
  - Berry, Frederick F., 1959 (Reel 5161, Frame 1014-1016)
  - Beseler Lantern Slide Company, 1941 (Reel 5161, Frame 1017-1022)
  - Bessemer, Auriel, 1941, 1968 (Reel 5161, Frame 1023-1031)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1942-1953 (Reel 5161, Frame 1032-1040)
  - Beta Sigma Phi Sorority, 1941 (Reel 5161, Frame 1041-1048)
  - Bettelheim, Ralph W., 1939 (Reel 5161, Frame 1049-1052)
  - Beverly Hills Library, 1941 (Reel 5161, Frame 1053-1058)
  - The Bezalel National Museum, 1954 (Reel 5161, Frame 1059-1061)
  - Biberman, Ed, 1953, 1963 (Reel 5161, Frame 1062-1068)
  - Biberman, Herbert, and Gale Sondergaard (see also: Sondergaard, Gale), 1961-1965 (Reel 5161, Frame 1069-1131)
  - Bibliographers, 1938-1941 (Reel 5161, Frame 1132-1160)
    (requests for information about Kent and his published works)
  - Bibliography, The Works of Rockwell Kent, 1930 (Reel 5161, Frame 1161-1303)
    (includes: correspondence, lists of individuals and institutions owning Kent work, bibliography of books illustrated and/or written by Kent, invitation list, miscellaneous documents, and manuscript)
  - Bickford, Arthur J., 1953 (Reel 5161, Frame 1304-1307)
  - Biddle, Fran, 1964 (Reel 5161, Frame 1308-1311)
  - Biddle, George, 1955-1956 (Reel 5161, Frame 1312-1330)
    (correspondence about reviews by Biddle and others of Kent's autobiography)
  - Bigelow, M. W., 1969 (Reel 5161, Frame 1331-1333)
  - Bills (see also: Paid Bills), 1945-1947 (Reel 5161, Frame unfilmed)
    (invoices, mainly for dairy equipment)
  - Bills (U.S. House of Representatives) (Reel 5161, Frame unfilmed)
  - Bingham, J. Fred, 1925 (Reel 5161, Frame 1336-1339)
  - Biographical Encyclopedia of the World, 1941-1942 (Reel 5161, Frame 1340-1348)
  - The Biosophical Institute, 1939 (Reel 5161, Frame 1349-1351)
  - Birchman, Willis, 1941-1947, undated (Reel 5161, Frame 1352-1399)
    (fan mail and correspondence about Art Young)
  - Birnbaum, Martin, 1919, 1922 (Reel 5161, Frame 1400-1404)
  - Birthday, 1952, 1955, 1957, 1959-1970 (Reel 5161, Frame 1405-1584)
    (greeting cards, letters and telegrams of congratulation, clippings, and replies from Kent)
  - Birthday, cont. (Reel 5162, Frame 3-691)
  - Bittner-Galland, 1938 (Reel 5162, Frame 692-694)
  - Bjarnason, Paul and Dora, 1958-1967 (Reel 5162, Frame 697-782)
    (correspondence about Kent's exhibition and trip to Moscow; other travels)
  - Black, Ruby (see also: Federal Fine Arts Department), 1937-1939 (Reel 5162, Frame 783-842)
    (correspondence regarding plans to replace Kent's Puerto Rican mural; also, printed matter concerning proposed Bureau of Fine Arts and the Puerto Rican needlework industry)
  - Blackford, John C., 1941 (Reel 5162, Frame 843-850)
  - Blair, Martha, 1935 (Reel 5162, Frame 851-874)
    (correspondence and legal papers concerning Blair's lease of a house from Kent)
  - Bligh, Thea, 1951-1965 (Reel 5162, Frame 875-1106)
    (correspondence about passport case, exhibition in the USSR and travel plans; also, family news and international politics)
  - Blitzstein, Marc, 1947 (Reel 5162, Frame 1107-1110)
  - Block, Gordon A., Jr., 1938 (Reel 5162, Frame 1111-1117)
  - Blodgett, Rev. F. P., 1941 (Reel 5162, Frame 1118-1122)
  - Bloom, A. Morton, 1945 (Reel 5162, Frame 1123-1151)
    (about World War II, and family news)
  - Bloom, Bessie, 1956 (Reel 5162, Frame 1152-1167)
    (about her book on Harry Dexter White)
  - Charles Bloom, Inc., 1950-1951, 1954 (Reel 5162, Frame 1168-1226)
    (regarding textile designs)
  - Bloomenthal, Aleck, 1965-1966 (Reel 5162, Frame 1227-1233)
  - Bloomfield, Marilyn, 1948-1949 (Reel 5162, Frame 1234-1240)
  - Bloor, Mother Ella Reeve, 1951 (Reel 5162, Frame 1241-1243)
  - Blowitz, Gertrude, 1952 (Reel 5162, Frame 1244-1284)
  - Blue, Genevieve, undated (Reel 5162, Frame 1285-1288)
  - Blue Ribbon Books, 1936-1937, 1941 (Reel 5162, Frame 1289-1320)
    (regarding book jacket designs)
  - Blum, A. Coleman, 1945 (Reel 5162, Frame 1321-1327)
  - Blum, Jerome, 1921 (Reel 5162, Frame 1328-1331)
  - Boardman, Mrs., 1942 (Reel 5162, Frame 1332-1334)
  - Boas, Franz, 1941 (Reel 5162, Frame 1335-1338)
  - Boehm, Otto and Paula, 1925-1939 (Reel 5162, Frame 1339-1446)
  - Bofman, Albert, 1957-1959, 1967 (Reel 5162, Frame 1447-1463)
  - Boissevain, Anne, 1943-1947 (Reel 5162, Frame 1464-1473)
  - Bola, Ronald J., 1960 (Reel 5162, Frame 1474-1478)
  - Bolen, James, 1941 (Reel 5162, Frame 1479-1482)
  - Bolotnikov, Nikita, 1965-1968 (Reel 5162, Frame 1483-1537)
  - Albert and Charles Boni, Inc. (see also: Creative Art), 1928-1930 (Reel 5162, Frame 1538-1565)
    (correspondence concerning book illustration and design, commission for Kent-designed bookends)
  - Albert and Charles Boni, Inc. (see also: Creative Art), 1930-1938 (Reel 5163, Frame 2-23)
  - Bonittas, Myrta, 1955, undated (Reel 5163, Frame 24-33)
  - Bonsel, Frederick A., 1948 (Reel 5163, Frame 34-37)
  - Book and Magazine Union (Book and Magazine Guild), 1940-1944 (Reel 5163, Frame 38-86)
    (regarding fund-raising and war relief efforts)
  - The Book & Print Shop, 1957 (Reel 5163, Frame 87-90)
  - Book Club of America, 1944 (Reel 5163, Frame 91-93)
  - Book Find Club, Inc., 1943-1944 (Reel 5163, Frame 94-130)
    (printed matter about club and request for Kent to design its logo)
  - The Book Mobilization, 1942 (Reel 5163, Frame 131-134)
  - Book-of-the-Month-Club, 1936-1938, 1946 (Reel 5163, Frame 135-156)
    (about commission to illustrate membership prospectus)
  - The Book Service Company, 1942 (Reel 5163, Frame 157-160)
  - Bookfinders, 1964-1971 (Reel 5163, Frame 161-238)
  - Bookplate Clients, 1938-1962, undated (Reel 5163, Frame 239-843)
    (correspondence about designs for individuals and libraries, with some samples; see also: Jobs)
  - Bookplates, 1969-1970 (Reel 5163, Frame 844-855)
    (correspondence and inquiries)
  - Bookplates by Others, 1940-1953, undated (Reel 5163, Frame 856-904)
    (letters from collectors requesting exchanges; samples)
  - Books, 1969 (Reel 5163, Frame 905-929)
    (correspondence with publishers; book orders, mainly for Wilderness)
  - Borressen, Peter and family, 1931, 1933 (Reel 5163, Frame 930-945)
  - Bosley, Homer, 1950 (Reel 5163, Frame 946-948)
  - Boss, Homer, 1956 (Reel 5163, Frame 949-952)
    (notice of memorial retrospective exhibition at Museum of New Mexico)
  - The Boston Antique Shop, 1946 (Reel 5163, Frame 953-956)
  - Boston Art Club, 1919 (Reel 5163, Frame 957-960)
  - The Boston Herald, 1941 (Reel 5163, Frame 961-964)
  - Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1933 (Reel 5163, Frame 965-967)
  - Boudin, Jean (Mrs. Leonard Boudin), 1962-1968 (Reel 5163, Frame 968-995)
  - Boudin, Kathy, 1961-1969 (Reel 5163, Frame 996-1036)
  - Boudin, Leonard B. (see: Attorneys) (Reel 5163)
  - Bowdoin College Museum of Art, 1968-1972 (Reel 5163, Frame 1038-1127)
    (correspondence concerning exhibition; appraisal of Kent Estate)
  - Boyer, Frank, 1947 (Reel 5163, Frame 1128-1131)
  - Boyer, Richard C., 1949 (Reel 5163, Frame 1132-1134)
  - Boyesen, Bayard and Priscilla, 1910-1921, 1935-1945, 1962 (Reel 5163, Frame 1135-1423)
    (correspondence about reviews of Salamina; Kent's advice about agents and publishers, with critiques of Boyesen's autobiography and plays; Kent's political activities and Boyesen's experiences in Communist Party; Boyesen Estate)
  - Boynton, Mary Fuertes, 1950 (Reel 5163, Frame 1424-1432)
  - Brace, Don and Ida, 1949-1954 (Reel 5163, Frame 1433-1443)
  - Bradshaw, Laurence and Eileen, 1965 (Reel 5163, Frame 1444-1448)
  - Bragg Brothers, 1947 (Reel 5163, Frame 1449-1451)
  - Bragman, Naomi, 1949 (Reel 5163, Frame 1452-1456)
  - Brasol, Boris and Maurice Leon, undated, 1939-1941 (Reel 5163, Frame 1457-1571)
    (printed matter about Brasol's association with Leon and their influence on Henry Ford's anti-Semitic and fascist ideas; also Nazi propaganda)
  - Brasol, Boris and Maurice Leon, cont. (Reel 5164, Frame 2-27)
  - Brassner, Julius, 1956 (Reel 5164, Frame 28-64)
    (regarding designs for glassware gift items)
  - Bray, Harry, 1946, 1955-1956 (Reel 5164, Frame 65-76)
  - Brazil, 1937-1938 (Reel 5164, Frame 77-307)
    (report on 1937 trip with Jerome Davis, representing the National Committee for People's Rights and the Joint Committee for the Defense of the Brazilian People, including: correspondence about the trip, notes, draft, and report; printed matter, including clippings, and transcripts of speech in Brazilian Senate; miscellaneous items concerning politics in Brazil)
  - Brentano's, 1944-1950 (Reel 5164, Frame 308-318)
    (book orders)
  - Brewer & Lord Insurance, 1948 (Reel 5164, Frame 319-321)
  - Brewer & Warren, Inc., 1930-1931 (Reel 5164, Frame 322-431)
    (regarding publication, promotion, and translation of N by E; contracts; see also: Putnam, George P.)
  - Brewing Industry Foundation, 1943 (Reel 5164, Frame 432-434)
  - Brewster, O. Byron, 1927-1953 (Reel 5164, Frame 435-694)
    (correspondence about family; marriage of Kathleen Kent; estate of Phelps Smith; forest preservation; personal legal business, including deeds and dairy license)
  - Bridges, Harry, 1940-1961 (Reel 5164, Frame 695-975)
    (includes form letters and other printed matter from Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges, Harry Bridges Defense Committee, and Harry Bridges Victory Committee; letters from Kent to public officials protesting impending deportation of Bridges; letters from Kent to Bridges about the outcome of the case and the importance of patronage to living artists)
  - Briehl, Walter and Marie, 1958-1967 (Reel 5164, Frame 976-1037)
    (correspondence concerning the Briehl's upcoming trip to the USSR, with requests for Kent's advice)
  - Bright, Marjorie, 1943 (Reel 5164, Frame 1038-1041)
  - Brin, Mabel, 1968 (Reel 5164, Frame 1042-1045)
  - Brinton, Christian, 1919 (Reel 5164, Frame 1046-1053)
  - British War Relief Society, 1941 (Reel 5164, Frame 1054-1059)
  - Broadcast Measurement Bureau Incorporated, 1946 (Reel 5164, Frame 1060-1062)
  - Brock, T., 1943 (Reel 5164, Frame 1063-1066)
  - Joseph R. Brodsky Memorial Committee, 1949 (Reel 5164, Frame 1067-1069)
  - The Brooklyn Museum and The Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, 1927-1929 (Reel 5164, Frame 1070-1105)
    (about reproduction permissions; gift to the museum; lecture; Kent's views on artists' rights over reproduction of their work; see also: United American Printmakers vs. Brooklyn Museum)
  - Brooks, Gladys, 1963 (Reel 5164, Frame 1106-1108)
  - Browder, Earl, undated, 1936, 1941-1956 (Reel 5164, Frame 1109-1193)
    (form letters and printed matter from Committee to Free Earl Browder; letters from Kent to public officials and friends requesting support for Browder; see also: Roosevelt, Franklin D. and Eleanor)
  - Brown, Allen, 1941 (Reel 5164, Frame 1194-1197)
  - Brown, Bob, 1959 (Reel 5164, Frame 1198-1202)
  - Brown, Lewis S., 1940-1951 (Reel 5164, Frame 1203-1270)
    (correspondence concerning Kent's attempts to help Brown get a WPA job; Brown's work on the anatomy of the horse and subsequent employment at American Museum of Natural History)
  - Brown, Robin, 1970-1971 (Reel 5164, Frame 1271-1316)
  - Brown, Ruth Shirley, 1945 (Reel 5164, Frame 1317-1321)
  - Brownell, Don Carlos, 1939-1945 (Reel 5164, Frame 1322-1335)
    (regarding Arctic and sub-Arctic development)
  - Browning, H. G., 1946, 1961-1967 (Reel 5164, Frame 1336-1349)
  - Bruce's Books, 1972 (Reel 5164, Frame 1350-1353)
  - Bruck, Lorraine (Associated Gallery of Art), 1955 (Reel 5164, Frame 1354-1357)
  - Brush, Helen S., 1947 (Reel 5164, Frame 1358-1361)
  - Bryan, Kit and Kitten, 1944-1949, undated (Reel 5164, Frame 1362-1419)
  - Bryant, Doris, 1948 (Reel 5164, Frame 1420-1422)
  - Bryden-Brown, Louise, 1958 (Reel 5164, Frame 1423-1434)
  - Buck, Seaver B., 1933, 1955, 1967 (Reel 5164, Frame 1435-1453)
    (arrangements for Gordon Kent to attend Berkshire School; reminiscences and family news)
  - W. S. Budworth & Son, 1928-1930, 1947 (Reel 5164, Frame 1454-1473)
    (arrangements for shipping paintings; see also: Exhibition Correspondence)
  - Budzislawski, Beate, 1949 (Reel 5164, Frame 1474-1478)
  - Bufano, Beniamino, 1957 (Reel 5164, Frame 1479-1482)
  - Buffalo Courier Express, 1942 (Reel 5164, Frame 1483-1485)
  - Buffalo Fine Arts Academy and Albright Art Gallery, 1933-1934 (Reel 5164, Frame 1486-1496)
    (correspondence concerning lecture and bookplate design)
  - Bulgaria, 1961-1970 (Reel 5164, Frame 1497-1549)
    (correspondence with friends in Bulgaria about family, travels, and politics)
  - Bulgaria, cont. (Reel 5165, Frame 2-104)
  - Bunker, M. N., 1941 (Reel 5165, Frame 105-107)
  - Bunzel, Joseph and Trudy, 1956-1971 (Reel 5165, Frame 108-271)
    (correspondence about exhibition in the USSR, travels, and family news; copy of Bunzel's "Outline for a Social History of Art")
  - Burchett, Wilfred, 1968 (Reel 5165, Frame 276-278)